Abhijeet Pradhanang

Full-stack developer | Software Engineer

abhipradhanang@gmail.com +9779840020253 | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Experience in frameworks like **Node.js**, **Nest.js**, **Vue.js**, **Nuxt.js**, **React.js**, **Typescript**, **Laravel**, **Semantic HTML**, **CSS3/Sass**, **AWS S3**, **AWS SQS**, **AWS SNS**. Responsible for developing technical documents and **roadmaps** by communicating with the stakeholder on a regular basis and **agile** (**Scrum**) development practitioner. Experience with developing the backend for web (SPA) and mobile applications. Responsible for the improvement of system design adhering to the **SOLID** principles as well as leading a team of developers and mentoring juniors.

EXPERIENCE

Codeware Lab Pvt. Ltd., Kathmandu, Nepal | Dec 2022 - present Senior Software Engineer

- Drive the development of admin applications for Shopify using Nest.js and React.js.
- Responsible for deploying applications through Heroku.
- Implemented csv imports for bulk resource imports.

Dimitra, Canada | Freelance | Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

Full-stack developer | Software Engineer

- Developed backend for the product Connected Farmer, Connected Coffee using Node.js, and Livestock Guru using Nest.js.
- Worked with **GraphQL Federation Gateway** to implement the micro-service architecture in Livestock Guru.
- Consumed Google Spreadsheet API to seed the data into the database.
- Documented APIs using Swagger docs.
- Implemented push notifications using Firebase.
- Communicated with designers and SMEs to understand and remove ambiguity in feature requests.
- Tech stacks: Nest.js with GraphQL, Node.js, Vue.js, MySQL, Google API, Firebase

Gurzu Inc, Lalitpur, Nepal | Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 Software Engineer

- Developed admin application for e-commerce using Shopify, Node.js
 (Nest.js), Typescript, React.js, MongoDB, AWS SQS, AWS SES, and AWS SNS.
- Designed NoSQL database with MongoDB.
- Implementation of **AWS SNS** for updating the store inventory through the notification service, **AWS SQS** for queuing webhooks sent by Shopify event bridge, and **AWS SES** for sending emails.
- Preparation of technical design documents with the proposed changes required to satisfy new business requirements along with conducting stand-up meetings.
- Implementation of **Bull Queue** to run background job queues.
- Implementation of the front end of admin apps using **Shopify Polaris**.
- Handle, develop, and maintain multiple Shopify projects.

Dzango, Hong Kong | Oct 2017 - Dec 2021

Software Engineer & Team Lead

- Developing corporate applications using Nest.js/Nuxt.js/Rest API, Typescript, Laravel/Vue.js/GraphQL, MySQL, and Docker with Gitlab CI for CI/CD in AWS server and Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
- Integration with payment gateways like PayPal, Omise along with Xero,
 Google Calendar API, and AWS S3 buckets for storage.
- Practiced TDD (Test Driven Development) using Jest, Cypress, and PHPUnit.
- Developed mobile application using the same codebase as web using
 Cordova for android and iPhone.
- Designed front-end applications from UI/UX tools like AdobeXD, Invision, and Figma using BEM (Block-Element-Modifier) styling convention.
- Implementation of security layers to verify the source of the request and use of **webhooks** as well.
- Designed **micro-service architecture** which includes auth server and content management system.
- Implementation of **Socket.io** used to build a chatting box.

PROJECTS

Flagship | Multi merchant Shopify projects | Nest.js, React.js, MongoDB,
 AWS SQS, AWS SNS, AWS SES, Shopify

- <u>Dimitra</u> | Platform for farmers regarding crops and livestocks | Node.js,
 Nest.js, Vue.js, Vuetify, GraphQL, Microservice with Federation Gateway
- Plizz | Xero Asia Partner of the Year 2021 | Accounting web application in Thailand | Nest.js, Nuxt.js, MySQL, GCP, Firebase
- <u>Belaws</u> | Expansion to 4 countries | Corporate service application | Laravel,
 Vue.js, MySQL, AWS S3, Docker
- SBAC | 5k users | Online English teaching web application for Thailand
 University | Freelance | Laravel, Vue.js, MySQL, AWS S3, Docker, Jitsi.meet
- Polifonic | Wiki application | Micro-service architecture | Laravel, Node.js,
 Vue.js, MySQL, MongoDB
- 4Clover Nepal | Inventory management for a local business | Node.js,
 React.js, Firebase
- AEDCAAN | Nepal Government aviation budgeting application | Freelance |
 Laravel, Vue.js
- <u>Kudomoments</u> | Online group card application | Freelance | Node.js, Nuxt.js,
 Digital Ocean space
- DzangoHQ | Employee management system | In house project | Laravel,
 Vue.js
- CollectivFood | London-based food supply application | Laravel, Vue.js,
 Cordova

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelors in Computer Engineering

- Kathmandu Engineering College, Kalimati, Kathmandu (2013 - 2017)

+2 in Physics

- St. Xaviers' College, Maitighar, Kathmandu (2011 - 2013)

School education

- Little Angels' School, Hattiban, Lalitpur

Business English Communication (Nov 2020 - Dec 2021)